The past is not what it seems.
Frozen II is a family, animation, adventure film directed by Jennifer Lee.
Elsa, Anna, Kristoff and Olaf head far into the forest to learn the
truth about an ancient mystery of their kingdom.
Elsa (voice), played by Idina Menzel.
Anna (voice), played by Kristen Bell.
Olaf (voice), played by Josh Gad.
Kristoff / Sven / Reindeers (voice), played by Jonathan Groff.
Iduna (voice), played by Evan Rachel Wood.
Mattias (voice), played by Sterling K. Brown.
Frozen 2, stylized as Frozen II, is a 2019 American animated musical
fantasy film produced by Walt Disney Animation Studios.
The second film in the Frozen franchise, following the 2013 film, it was directed by Chris Buck and Jennifer Lee and
written by Lee, from a story they conceived with Marc Smith, Kristen Anderson-Lopez, and Robert Lopez.
It stars the voices of Kristen Bell, Idina Menzel, Josh Gad, and Jonathan Groff.
Set three years after the events of the first film, Frozen 2 follows sisters Anna and Elsa, and their companions
Kristoff, Sven, and Olaf as they travel to an enchanted forest to unravel the origin of Elsa's magical power.
Frozen 2 was greenlit in March 2015 after a company debate about
whether it would be perceived as inferior to the original.
It used more-complex, enhanced animation technology compared to the
first film, and was an interdepartmental collaboration.
Anderson-Lopez and Lopez returned as the film's songwriters,
and Christophe Beck again composed the score.
The film was translated into 46 languages and was accompanied by Into
the Unknown: Making Frozen 2, a documentary series.
Frozen 2 premiered in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on November 7, 2019,
and was released in the United States on November 22.
It received generally positive reviews from critics, although
it was considered inferior to its predecessor.
The film grossed $1.450 billion worldwide, finishing its theatrical run as the third-highest-grossing film of 2019,
the tenth-highest-grossing film in history, and the second-highest-grossing animated film of all time.
It also held the title of the highest-grossing worldwide
opening for an animated film for three years.
Frozen 2 received a nomination for Best Original Song at the 92nd
Academy Awards, among numerous other accolades.
A sequel, Frozen 3, is scheduled to be released in 2027.
The film explores themes of princess, magic, kingdom, winter, queen.
The tone is lighthearted.